你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我听说可以打个洞
I heard you could punch a hole in these
就能让它变成双面的
and make them double-sided.
这样你就有双倍储存空间吗
Then it would have more storage?
是啊  可是我没付双面软盘的钱啊
Yes, but I didn't pay for a double-sided floppy disk.
那又如何
So?
所以这是个道德难题啊
So it's an ethical dilemma.
我们下一节课得在更衣室洗澡
We have to take a shower in the locker room next period,
你现在居然有心情担心这个
and that's what you're worried about?
我在裤子里穿好了泳裤
Actually, I have a bathing suit under my pants.
那女孩拿了一本地质统计学的书
That girl just took a book on geostatistics.
那又如何
Yeah, so?
那并不是任何科学课要求阅读的读物
That's not required reading for any science course.
或许她是想拿去拍死蜘蛛呢
Maybe she wants to squash a spider with it.
不是  你看  她在读
No, look, she's reading it.
这个神秘的女人是谁啊
Who is this mystery woman?
我们该邀请她来共进午餐吗
Should we invite her to have lunch with us?
不知道啊  至今为止一直只有我俩
I don't know. So far, it's just been you and me,
我们能确定合得来
and we know that works.
你真的想要冒合不来的风险吗
Do we really want to mess with success?
你可以把这个当做是个实验
We could think of it as an experiment.
你还真是懂我的弱点啊
Oh, you do know how to push my buttons.
好啦  去问她
All right, go ask her.
为什么是我去
Why me?
你的睾酮缺乏令你在女性眼中很可爱
Your lack of testosterone makes you adorable to women.
这我无从反驳
I can't argue with that.
你好
Hello.
你好啊
我叫谢尔顿
My name is Sheldon.
我知道你是谢尔顿·库珀
Yeah, you're Sheldon Cooper.
你认识我吗
You know who I am?
整个高中只有一个9岁的人
Well, there's only one nine-year-old in high school,
而你还有没换完的乳牙
and you still have your baby teeth.
她认识我  情况很顺利
She knows who I am. It's going well.
找我有什么事
What do you want?
你愿意跟我与我朋友一起共进午餐吗
Would you like to have lunch with me and my friend?
为什么
Why?
为什么不呢
Why else?
这样我们才能热烈地聊地质统计学啊
So we can have a spirited conversation about geostatistics.
你真的跟大家说的一样聪明啊
You really are as smart as everybody says.
我的牙齿虽小  但我的前额皮质超巨大
My teeth are small, but my prefrontal cortex is enormous.
♪ 世上没人比我强壮 ♪
♪ Nobody else is stronger than I am ♪
♪ 昨天我移了一座山 ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ 我相信我能当你的英雄 ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ 我是个了不起的小家伙 ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
少
年
谢尔顿
随着莉比的加入
The addition of Libby brought
我们午餐期间的聊天深度也有所提升
a level of sophistication to our lunchtime discussion.
她妈妈还为她多带了起司条
Her mom also packed extra string cheese,
这广为人知的社交润滑剂
which is a well-known social lubricant.
你以后要当地质学家
You're gonna be a geologist.
太有意思了
That's fascinating.
你为什么选这领域呢
Why'd you choose that?
在我小时候  我的爷爷奶奶带我去
When I was a little girl, my grandparents took me
卡尔斯巴德洞窟国家公园时迷上了
to Carlsbad Caverns, and I was hooked.
探索洞窟  太酷了
Exploring caves, that is super cool.
我不同意  黑暗又封闭的空间令我恐惧
Disagree. Dark, enclosed spaces are terrifying.
我头套进衣服时都会被吓到
I get scared putting on a sweatshirt.
我看过那场面
Hmm. ‭I've seen it.
挺有娱乐效果
Pretty entertaining.
你想好上大学要选什么专业了吗
Do you know what you're going to major in in college?
我倾向选量子色动力学  但谁知道呢
I'm leaning towards quantum chromodynamics, but who knows?
要我几年前回答  我会答玩具小火车
A few years ago, I would've said choo-choo trains.
那你呢
What about you?
当然是地质学
Oh, geology for sure.
真的吗
Really?
你什么时候决定的
When did you decide that?
很久以前啊  吃你的苹果片
A long time ago. Eat your apple slices.
我们每天都在图书馆用餐
So we eat in the library every day.
欢迎你加入我们
You're welcome to join us.
比在食堂吃好多了
It's much better than the cafeteria.
又安静  又不太会有人丢食物到我们身上
It's quiet, and a lot less food gets thrown at us.
好啊  或许我明天再来找你们大伙儿
Yeah. Maybe I'll see y'all tomorrow.
好
Right.
大伙儿有机会明天见
Maybe y'all will.
莉比  再见啦
Bye, Libby.
还"大伙儿"呢
"Y'all"?
我是在试着同化
I'm assimilating.
你闭嘴
Shut up.
今天学校如何啊
So how was school today?
谢尔顿交了女朋友
Sheldon's got a girlfriend.
-什么  -你乱说
- What? - That's not true.
是真的  我看到他在学校跟那女孩说话了
Oh, yes, it is. I seen him talking to her at school.
谢尔顿·李·库珀  你个小色胚
Sheldon Lee Cooper, you dog.
她可爱吗
Is she cute?
跟什么东西比
Compared to what?
她读几年级
What grade is she in?
11年级
Eleventh.
还是比你大的御姐啊
An older woman.
赞啊
Nice.
几乎所有人都比我大啊
Most everybody's older than me.
这有什么好赞的
Why is that nice?
所以你觉得如何  乔治
So what do you think, George?
是时候跟他"聊聊"了吗
Is it time to have "the talk" with him?
聊什么
What talk?
不聊  没人要聊
No talk. Nobody's talking.
如果"聊聊"是指有关人类繁衍的事情
If "the talk" is in regards to human reproduction,
我已经知道是怎么个流程了
I already understand how that works.
你怎么会知道这些
How do you know that?
我告诉他的
I told him.
我的老天啊
Oh, Lord.
所以  我们的小圈子
And so, our little social circle
从两个人变成了三个人
grew from two to three.
一个早期的我能吸引所有人到我身边的例子
An early example of how people are just drawn to me.
你的意思是说  如果没有地质学
Are you saying that without geology,
世界上就不会有进化论吗
there'd be no theory of evolution?
地质学家查尔斯·莱尔教导达尔文
Charles Lyell taught Charles Darwin
地球比我们所有人认为的还要古老许多
the Earth was much, much older than anyone thought,
这给了达尔文勇气去发现
which gave Darwin the courage to figure out
所有的生物是在亿年多的时间里进化而来
all species evolved over billions of years.
这很不错  我可以用这个点
That's good. I can use that
去让我主日学校的牧师难堪
to humiliate my pastor at Sunday school.
我不知道哪个比较美
I don't know what's more beautiful,
是你美丽的大脑还是双眸
your mind or your eyes.
丹  别这样
Tam, please.
我们在吃饭呢
We're eating.
你知道暗中监视小孩很变态吧
You know spying on kids is creepy.
我不是在暗中监视小孩  是在监视你弟弟
I wasn't spying on kids, I was s-spying on your brother.
那你为什么不直接进去看
Why won't you just go inside?
直接进去就不是暗中监视了吧
Well, then, it wouldn't be spying, now would it?
你惊讶什么
Oh, what?
你没说她是黑人啊
You didn't mention she was black.
我应该提吗
Was I supposed to?
不用  当然不需要啊
No, 'course not.
那你说这个干嘛
Then why bring it up?
只是跟我预想中的不一样嘛
It just wasn't what I was expecting.
那你本来预想中的是什么样的
What were you expecting?
这学校很大
It's a big school.
你为什么一定要在这里
Why are you right here?
图书馆里有人权斗士马丁·路德·金的书
They've got some books in there about Martin Luther King.
或许你该进去读一读
Maybe you should go read one.
早安
Morning.
所以为什么人们花了那么久的时间
So why did it take people so long
才愿意相信大陆漂移说呢
to believe in continental drift,
很明显能看出非洲跟南美洲
when it's obvious that Africa and South America
-像拼图一样能吻合啊  -才没有呢
- fit together like a puzzle? - No, they don't.
人们不理解大陆漂移说
People didn't understand continental drift
是因为他们不懂海底扩张学说
because they didn't understand seafloor spreading.
怎么了
What?
你的智慧
I'm both threatened
令我受到威胁又为之折服
and delighted by your brain.
我只有为之折服
I'm just delighted by it.
还真能合上
They do fit.
这太神奇了吧
That's nuts.
地质学家喜欢在生活中让自己"沉淀"下来
"Geologists lead a sedimentary lifestyle."
莉比  你这双关有意思
Libby, that is a good one.
你敢相信他这个样子吗
Can you believe what's going on with him?
对啊
I know.
他都快跟那女孩聊了一个小时电话了
He's been on the phone with that girl for almost an hour.
谢尔顿交了女朋友
Sheldon's got a girlfriend.
谁能想到有这可能
What are the odds?
那女孩才不是女朋友
She's not a girlfriend,
两个人只是精神交流
it's more of a mental rapport.
一切都是这么开始的
That's where it starts.
我就是用我超凡的智慧赢得你心
I did win you over with my superior intellect.
明明是你的机车  你自己清楚
It was your motorcycle and you know it.
幸好她不是被你的猛男体格所迷惑
Good thing it wasn't your masculine physique,
因为那早已一去不复返了
because that is long gone.
你以为我留着那机车是为什么
Why do you think I kept the motorcycle?
为什么他可以煲电话粥而我不行
How come he gets to tie up the phone and I can't?
因为发生在他身上的事叫神迹
Because what is happening in there is called a miracle,
而敬畏神的信徒是不会去阻止神迹的
and God-fearing people do not get in the way of those.
小乔治
Hey, Georgie,
如果哪天你能找到女朋友
if you ever find a girlfriend,
或许你能跟你弟弟他们四人约会啊
maybe you can go on a double date with your brother.
那女孩不是他女朋友
She's not his girlfriend.
我也交得到啊
And I can find one...
我只是没在找女朋友而已
I'm just not looking.
是啊  那的确是地质学的笑话
Yes, that was a geology joke.
或许我们应该在《体育画报泳装特辑》
We gotta get that Sports Illustrated swimsuit issue
毁了他人生之前  先把它收走
away from him before he's ruined forever.
莉比莉比莉比啊
Oh, Libby, Libby, Libby.
到底发生什么了
What is happening?
当时所发生的事呢
What was happening was,
也发生在许多男性身上
like many men before me,
我被有着异域风情的地质学所迷惑了
I was being seduced by the exotic world of geology.
我们在附近的山涧里寻找着玻陨石
We searched for tektites in a nearby ravine.
玻陨石就是天然玻璃
Tektites are natural glass
是在陨石撞击后形成的
formed during meteorite impacts.
它们也与浣熊粪便十分相似
They also bear a close resemblance to raccoon feces,
所以我聪明地开始了"不碰玻陨石"政策
so I wisely adopted a "no touching tektites" policy.
这叫完全解理[完美乳沟]
It's called perfect cleavage
当石膏分离地如此干净时的称呼
when gypsum separates this cleanly.
我当时好为丹感到骄傲
I was so proud of Tam
他没有开幼稚的乳沟玩笑
for not making an immature cleavage joke.
快看我  我在摸乳沟
Look at me, I'm touching cleavage.
他说完那感觉就消失了
Until he made one.
而晶洞玉石就像是大自然的皮纳塔
And, like Mother Nature's pinata,
皮纳塔是一种装满糖果或玩具的纸糊容器
通常在生日会上悬挂并让人击打到掉出奖品
它的里面也含有秘密的惊喜
geodes contained a secret surprise inside.
而且你不用忍受
But you didn't have to suffer
参加生日派对的痛苦就能享受惊喜
through a birthday party to enjoy it.
怎么样了
How's it going?
我想我找出问题所在了
Well, I think I figured out the problem.
问题在哪
What is it?
我对修机械一窍不通
I'm a terrible mechanic.
-怎么啦  -这个嘛
- What's up? ‭- Well,
谢尔顿最近花了不少时间
Sheldon's been spending quite a bit of time
跟那叫莉比的女孩混在一起
with this Libby girl, lately.
所以呢
Yeah, so?
他还那么小
So isn't he a little young
交青少年的朋友真的好吗
to be hanging with teenagers?
他只是身体还小
Oh, he's only young on the outside.
他心里就是个老头
Inside, he's an old man.
我是说认真的
I'm being serious.
我也是啊
So am I.
再给他别上领结  他外表也老了
And with that bowtie, he's old on the outside, too.
我不该来问你的
Sorry I bothered.
等一下
Hang on.
我们送他去念高中时
What did you think was gonna happen
你以为会怎么样
when we sent him to high school?
我哪知道  他会学习新知识
I don't know, that he'd learn stuff,
然后回到家里  永远当我的小宝贝
and then, come back home and be my baby forever.
玛丽  这对他是好事
Mare, it's good for him.
再过两年他也许就要上大学了  到时怎么办
He may start college in a couple years, what happens then?
我瞬间想到的答案是  我跟他住一间宿舍
Off the top of my head, he and I share a dorm room.
要不是觉得你真可能这么做  这话还挺好笑的
You know I'd laugh at that if I didn't kind of believe you.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我想上厕所  但里面有时会不太文明
I need to use the bathroom, but it can get uncivilized in there.
现在里面有人吗
Anyone in there now?
我不知道  我不敢去找出答案
I don't know. I was afraid to find out.
男厕
厕所有人吗
Anybody in here?
去吧
Go ahead.
我守在外面
I'll stand guard.
我之前的人生你都跑哪儿去了
Where have you been all my life?
想都别想
I don't think so.
我要尿尿
I gotta pee.
那是你的问题  一边儿去
That's your problem. Keep moving.
-谢谢你  -不客气
- Thank you. - ‭Happy to help.
1点45分时你能来站岗吗
Is there any chance you'd be available to stand guard at 1:45?
你还有上厕所还有时间表吗
You have a bathroom schedule?
你没有吗
You don't?
回见
See you later.
那些说抓住一个男人
Whoever said the quickest way to a man's heart
要先抓住他的胃的人
is through his stomach
没考虑过自己的小膀胱
did not consider his tiny bladder.
我觉得至今取得最好的航天飞机名是"探索号"
I think the best space shuttle name so far is Discovery.
那"挑战者号"呢
What about Challenger?
-太咄咄逼人  -"亚特兰蒂斯号"呢
- Too in-your-face. - Atlantis?
一个浮不起来的虚构岛屿
A fictional island that couldn't stay afloat?
烂得很彻底
I don't think so.
-还有"企业号"啊  -是没错
- There's the Enterprise. - ‭There is,
出现在《星际迷航》里  就该待那里面
and it's on Star Trek, where it belongs.
你知道吗  自然科学博物馆
You know they're playing a space shuttle movie
正在放一部航天飞机电影
at the Museum of Natural Science.
-还是巨幕电影呢  -我也听说了
- It's in IMAX. - I heard about that.
屏幕好像会超级大
The screen is supposed to be huge.
那里还在举办地质学展览
‭They also have a great geology exhibit.
可是博物馆在休斯顿
Well, it's in Houston--
-我们该怎么去呢  -我来开车
- how are we gonna get there? - I'll drive.
我很想跟你一起看电影
Oh, I would love to see a movie with you.
你不用先征得你父母同意吗
Don't you need to ask your parents first?
-不用  谢尔顿  -但他们不会担心你在哪儿吗
- No, Sheldon, I don't. - But won't they worry where you are?
他们不会担心的
They'll be fine.
算我一个
Count me in.
真庆幸你不是我儿子
Glad you're not my son.
现在他想跟他们去休斯顿看电影
And now he wants to see a movie in Houston with them.
为什么要去休斯顿
Why Houston?
我不知道  那边有"锯木"技术之类的
I don't know, it's in MixMax or something.
你意思是我得开车去休斯顿吗
So you're saying I got to drive to Houston?
不  那姑娘莉比开车
No. This girl Libby's gonna drive.
太好了
Great.
一点都不好  乔治
It's not great, George.
我可不希望我儿子坐上
I don't want my little boy in some car
由青少年驾驶的车
with a teenager behind the wheel.
所有高中生都开车
All high school kids drive.
是吗  反正我不喜欢
Yeah? Well, I don't like it.
我小的时候
Would you let me get in a car
你会让我坐陌生人的车吗
with a stranger when I was young?
没人约过你出去  所以没什么所谓
Well, nobody ever asked you out, so it didn't really matter.
我想跟你聊聊
Hey. I want to talk to you.
等等  我先把火车停入车站
Hold on. Let me bring this into the station
才不会让通勤乘客们失望
so as not to disappoint my commuters.
他们想回到家人身边
They'd like to get home to their families.
我考虑了很久  恐怕我不能允许你
I gave it a lot of thought, and I'm afraid I can't allow you
跟朋友开车去休斯顿
to drive to Houston with your friends.
为什么
Why?
亲爱的  你还是个小孩子
Well, honey, you're still a little boy.
我觉得这样不对
I don't think it's right.
我不是小孩子了  我是高中生了
I'm not a little boy. I'm a high school student.
对不起  但我心意已决
I'm sorry, I made up my mind.
如果你真的很想看这部电影
If you'd really like to see this movie,
我愿意开车载你去
I'm willing to drive you.
或许我们可以和你朋友在那会合
Maybe we could meet your friends there.
我不想要我妈咪带我去
I don't want my mommy to take me.
那你就别想去了
Well, then, you're not going.
愤怒是一种丑陋的情绪
Anger is an ugly emotion.
狂怒更是如此
Unbridled rage even more so.
当我内心充满怒火时
And when it bubbled up inside me,
我用唯一懂得的方式来转化这种情绪
I channeled it the only way I knew how.
我仿佛着了魔一样  给房子彻底大扫除
I cleaned the house like a man possessed.
我听不见奥普拉说话了
I can't hear Oprah!
关我鸟事
I don't care!
谢尔顿  我需要进去
Sheldon, I need to get in there.
去姥姥家上大号吧
Poop at Meemaw's!
你漏了这里没擦  怪胎
You missed a spot, weirdo.
我看到了
I see it.
他这副样子  我该这么办
What am I supposed to do with this?
在他的精力用光前  赶紧送去我家
Send him over to my house before he runs out of gas.
好吧  我们谈笔交易
All right, I'll make a deal with you.
我在听
I'm listening.
你可以跟朋友们去休斯顿
You can go to Houston with your friends,
但我想先见见这个女孩
but I want to meet this girl first.
合乎情理
That's very reasonable.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
你能把烘干纸拿下来吗
Now, can you please reach the dryer sheets?
我站上梯凳会头晕
I get vertigo on the step stool.
我常被人形容
I've often been accused
顽固不化  恣意妄为
of being stubborn and willful,
但有时这招很有用
but sometimes it works like gangbusters.
请进
Please come in.
请坐
Have a seat.
你家很漂亮
You have a beautiful home.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thank you. - ‭Thank you.
希望你能原谅我  我就想见见
I hope you'll forgive me, I just wanted to meet
开车载我9岁儿子去休斯顿的人
the person driving my nine-year-old son to Houston.
我能理解
I understand.
我也是
Me, too.
我没跟你说话  丹
I wasn't talking to you, Tam.
还有  我想确定一下
And I just wanted to make certain
你没被开过罚单
that you've had no traffic tickets
更重要的是  没出过意外
or, heaven forbid, accidents.
没有  女士  我开车很小心
No, ma'am. I'm a very safe driver.
-你完全不必担心  -很好
- You've got nothing to worry about. ‭- Good.
很好  你以前开车去过休斯顿吗
Good. Have you made this trip before?
开过几次
A few times, yes.
你吸大麻吗
Mm-hmm. You smoke marijuana?
-妈妈  -不吸  女士
- Mom! - ‭No, ma'am.
勇敢说不[反大麻口号]
Just say no.
好吧
Well...
这让我很放心
I find this very reassuring.
我得承认
I have to admit,
我本来有些担忧  但是
I had some trepidation, but...
见过你之后  我感觉好多了
having met you, I'm feeling a lot better.
那就好  你没什么可担心的  库珀太太
Good. You've got nothing to worry about, Mrs. Cooper.
我有多年看顾小孩的经验
I've been babysitting kids for years.
看顾小孩  看顾小孩
Babysitting... babysitting...
看顾小孩
Babysitting.
看顾小孩  看顾小孩
Babysitting... babysitting...
我有多年看顾小孩的经验
I've been babysitting kids for years.
恕我失陪
Excuse me.
我不太舒服
I don't feel well.
他们自己去吧  我去不了了
They'll have to go without me.
谢利  你没事吧
Shelly, you okay?
有事
No.
你想谈谈吗
You want to talk about it?
不想
No.
想一个人待会吗
You want me to leave you alone?
不想
No.
我本来以为和莉比是平辈相交
I thought Libby and I were equals,
谁知道她将我视为小孩子
but she thinks of me as a child.
很遗憾  宝贝
I'm sorry, baby.
现在这样叫我是雪上加霜
Calling me that isn't helping right now.
也是  对不起
Right. Sorry.
她的年纪几乎是你的两倍
She is almost twice your age.
有些人年纪比我大五倍
There are people five times my age
还是比我蠢啊
that are stupider than me.
这跟聪明没关系
This is not about being smart.
-那还跟什么有关系  -这个嘛
- What else is there? - ‭Well...
人有不同种的成熟
there's other kinds of maturity.
怎么了
What's up?
不关你的事
None of your business.
他为什么哭了
Why is he crying?
再说一遍  不关你的事
Again, it's none of your business.
请你离开
Please go.
好吧  塞莱斯特和我都很上道
Fine. Celeste and I know when we aren't wanted.
我们刚说到哪儿了
Where were we?
各种各样的成熟
Different kinds of maturity.
没错
That's right.
有情感上的成熟  身体上的成熟
There's emotional maturity, physical maturity,
很多都跟聪明与否无关
all things that have nothing to do with being smart.
你是在说我情感上不成熟吗
Are you suggesting I'm not emotionally mature?
我只是暗示这一点
I was hinting at it.
不管怎样  我都不想再交朋友了
Regardless, I'm not interested in making any more friends.
我想那不是你真实的想法
Oh, I don't think that's how you really feel.
就是的
It is.
从今以后  我要过上隐士般的生活
From now on, it's a hermit's life for me.
我很肯定  你长大后
I bet, when you grow up, you will be surrounded
会交到很多聪明  优秀的朋友
by lots of smart, wonderful friends.
我觉得那是不可能的
I can't see that happening.
反正
Well,
主自有他的安排
the Lord works in mysterious ways.
你又要搬出神的那一套了
And here we go with the God talk.
你好
Hey.
巨幕电影看得怎么样了
How was the IMAX movie?
这个嘛
Well...
好的  状态  找到他们了吗
Okay, status. Find them?
去吧  指引...
Go. Guidance...
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你觉得我在干什么
What do you think I'm doing?
把爪子收回去  否则我把它拧断
Move your arm before I rip it off.
气氛变得有些尴尬
It got a little uncomfortable.
为什么
Why is that?
莉比对我有意思
Libby's got feelings for me,
但我觉得保持朋友关系比较好
but I think it's better we just stay friends.
最近我又思考了一下地质学
I've been giving geology some more thought.
结果呢
Yeah, and?
我决定了  那不是真正的科学
I've decided it's not really a science.
-不是吗  -不是  比较像是爱好
- It's not? - No, it's more like a hobby.
收集石头
Rock collecting.
挺幼稚的
Childish, really.
我懂你意思
I can see that.
如你们所见
As you can see,
有时一个绝顶聪明的人
sometimes a person can be both incredibly intelligent
也会满口胡言
and full of baloney.